<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>infrastructure</name>
		<update version="0.0.11">
			<file name="infrastructure.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3axAttack207/worldscollide/master/homebrew/infrastructure.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Worlds Collide" type="Source" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_SOURCE_WORLDSCOLLIDE">
		<description>
			<p>Worlds Collide Homebrew</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">WC</set>
			<set name="url">https://github.com/3axAttack207/worldscollide</set>
			<set name="author" url="https://github.com/3axAttack207">/3axAttack207</set>
			<set name="homebrew">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- grant this in the class, for use in requirements for rules -->

	<element name="Worlds Collide Requirement" type="Grants" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT"/>
	
	<!-- weapon properties -->

	<element name="Timely Reload" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TIMELYRELOAD">
		<description>
			<p>Timely Reload: You must use your entire turn (all movement, actions, and bonus actions) to reload, and during the reload, you will be unable to use reactions.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Magazine" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_MAGAZINE">
		<description>
			<p>Magazine: This weapon uses a magazine that holds a specific number of rounds (different per weapon). When the magazine is empty, it must be replaced with a new one. Reloading will use a bonus action, unless stated otherwise.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Recoil" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_RECOIL">
		<description>
			<p>Recoil: When attacking, not all of your attacks will hit due to recoil. When you land a hit, at least one round will hit (can be different per weapon), then roll a dice, depending on the number of attacks used (weapons will have different dice), the number rolled on the dice will add damage die. This can be canceled out by mounting the weapon, if possible.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Extremely Heavy" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_EXTREMELYHEAVY">
		<description>
			<p>Extremely Heavy: Having this item in your inventory or on your person reduces your speed by 10ft.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Heavy Recoil" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_HEAVYRECOIL">
		<description>
			<p>Heavy Recoil: When you fire at a target multiple times in succession. For every attack after the first, your attack roll will have a -3 penalty (recoil), and this stacks every time you fire on the same target. If you end your turn attacking and start your next turn attacking with the same weapon, you keep your previous penalty. This can be reset by switching targets, using a different action, using your bonus action, or using your reaction. This can be reduced to a -1 by mounting the weapon, if possible.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Automatic" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AUTOMATIC">
		<description>
			<p>Automatic: The weapons attack action can attack multiple times a turn based on its rate of fire and how many rounds left available.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Semi-Automatic" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SEMIAUTOMATIC">
		<description>
			<p>Semi-Automatic: The weapons attack action can attack three times a turn (unless stated otherwise) on anyone.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Explosive Ammunition" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_EXPLOSIVEAMMUNITION">
		<description>
			<p>Explosive Ammunition: On contact, the target and all creatures within 5ft of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC 10+Proficiency+Dexterity). On a failed save, they take full damage, and on a successful save, they take half damage.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Sidearms" type="Weapon Property" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SIDEARMS">
		<description>
			<p>Sidearm: If you have a free hand and a bonus action, you can draw your sidearm and fire it as a bonus action, but unable to add any bonuses to the attack roll. You also dont roll at disadvantage from being to close to your target.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<!--  weapon groups  -->

		<element name="Weapon Group (Firearms)" type="Weapon Group" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_FIREARMS"/>
		<element name="Weapon Group (Light Machine Guns)" type="Weapon Group" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_LIGHTMACHINEGUNS"/>
		<element name="Weapon Group (Sniper Rifles)" type="Weapon Group" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_SNIPERRIFLES"/>
		<element name="Weapon Group (Launchers)" type="Weapon Group" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_LAUNCHERS"/>

	<!-- proficiencies -->

	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (Light Machine Guns)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LIGHTMACHINEGUNS">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_LIGHTMACHINEGUNS</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_KALASHNIKOVPKP"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (Sniper Rifles)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SNIPERRIFLES">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_SNIPERRIFLES</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_M110SASS"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapons Proficiency (Launchers)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LAUNCHERS">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_LAUNCHERS</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_GRENADELAUNCHER"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Specific Weapon Proficiency-->

	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (Kalashnikov PKP)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_KALASHNIKOVPKP">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_KALASHNIKOVPKP</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Proficiency with the Kalashnikov PKP light machine gun. Grants ability to use the weapon without penalties and enables related actions and rules.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (M110 SASS)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_M110SASS">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_M110SASS</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Proficiency with the M110 SASS sniper rifle. Grants ability to use the weapon without penalties and enables related actions and rules.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (Grenade Launcher)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_GRENADELAUNCHER">
		<supports>ID_WC_WEAPON_GRENADELAUNCHER</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Proficiency with the Grenade Launcher. Grants ability to use the weapon without penalties and enables related actions and rules.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<!-- Specific Armor Proficiency -->

	<element name="Armor Proficiency (Jugernaught Altyn)" type="Proficiency" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_JUGERNAUTALTYN">
		<supports>ID_WC_ARMOR_HEAVY_JUGERNAUTALTYN</supports>
		<requirements>ID_WC_GRANTS_WORLDSCOLLIDE_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Proficiency with the Jugernaught Armor w/ Altyn. Grants ability to use the armor without penalties and enables related actions and rules.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<!-- This Enchantment is used for a certin character in Worlds Collide -->

	<element name="Man's Best Friend" type="Magic Item" source="Worlds Collide" id="ID_WC_MAGIC_ITEM_MANS_BEST_FRIEND">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon, hidden deep within the confines of a mad laboratory, is a strange conglomeration of science and necromancy, and appears to be a human wizard and a magic using gunslinger’s attempt to keep their favorite pet around after its passing. The brain itself, or at least a piece of it is floating in a jar attached to the body of the gun, and the sights are arranged with two floppy ear like mechanisms. The face of the deceased animal is painted either on the body itself or around the sights, and magic runes of necromancy are engraved into its barrel.</p>
			<p class="indent">Only a gunslinger or a wizard can attune to this weapon. Any other creatures attempting to do so will be growled at by the weapon and fail to attune to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this odd sentient firearm. It has the following additional properties. Sentience. Man’s Best Friend contains the soul of a friendly dog with an Intelligence of 6, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 8. It has 60 feet of darkvision, and also has advantage on saving throws on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon can understand Common, any language its previous masters knew and any language you know while attuned to it. It communicates in barks, yips, whines and growls that are audible out to 60 feet. However, it can translate those barks when speaking directly to you as primal feelings and emotions, such as fear, excitement or sadness.</p>
			<p>Personality. Man’s Best Friend is extraordinarily curious, and will constantly try to direct you towards interesting things, such as caves, treasure, and squirrels. It is extremely loyal to you once you form a bond to it, and will growl whenever it senses dangerous intentions from other creatures, or pant happily in the presence of creatures friendly to you. The weapon can move ever so slightly in your grip, but never enough to force your aim off or drop it. It usually does this when it wishes to be pet. Man’s Best Friend thrives on affection and assurance, and if those things are not regularly provided to it by its wielder, a conflict between the two will occur after 10 consecutive days of neglect.</p>
			<p class="indent">Nose For Danger. This weapon makes Wisdom (Perception) rolls whenever it chooses to check for hostile creatures within range of its senses, rolled by the DM. If it senses any, the ears perk up on the gun and it begins to emit a low growl. It will roll Wisdom (Insight) checks every minute you spend in the presence of a creature that is indifferent to you or does not know you personally. If it senses ill intent or hostility, it will react similarly.</p>
			<p class="indent">Bloodhound. Man’s Best Friend can cast find traps and 5th level hunter’s mark once per long rest. It decides when to cast these spells, and will maintain concentration on the latter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Guard Gun. When in combat, the gun will bark viciously when attacking, and will yip and whine when its wielder is badly hurt. The gun can take its own actions in combat, and will always take its turn before its wielder in the initiative order. The gun can use its action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check or give a bark of encouragement to you, granting you a d4 to use on your next attack roll or saving throw for 1 minute or until used.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any firearm</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any firearm">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_WC_WEAPON_GROUP_FIREARMS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Man’s Best Friend</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>